Capital District Senior Issues Forum; Records apap384
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Capital District Senior Issues Forum Records
1997-2018
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap384
1.0 cubic ft.
This collection contains the day-to-day work of the Capital District Senior Issues Forum.
Content Description
This collection includes administrative materials, newsletters, event programs, correspondence, award materials, and legislative materials. Also contains biographical information on award members.
Biographical Note
CDSIF began as a pilot program in the late 90s focused on senior housing provision. The forum moved its headquarters from Westminster Presbyterian Church to Catholic Charities in 1999-2000 and established formal governance structure, which included an all-volunteer member Steering Committee and an Advisory Committee. The voluntary initiative organization is composed of faith communities, organizations, and individuals. Forum members come together to identify and address issues of concern for older seniors in the Capital District of New York, generate support within the faith communities, educate the Capital District about senior needs, and recognize the accomplishments of older seniors.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged chronologically. There are no series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Kitt Jackson donated all materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in January 2020.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Capital District Senior Issues Forum; Senior Citizens; Older people--New York (State)
- Senior Citizen Housing Project, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- CDSIF Senior Lifetime Achievement Ceremony, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CDSIF Sponsored Bills Legislation, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Eldercare Hotline Report/Feasibility Study Outline, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Support Memorandum, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cooling Off Bill, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Senior Citizen Housing, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Westminster Presbyterian/Sr. Housing Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lifetime Achievements of Capital Region Seniors (1 of 2), 1998-2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lifetime Achievements of Capital Region Seniors (2 of 2), 1998-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Caregiving Strategic Brainstorming for Seniors, 1998-2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Awards: Lifetime Achievement/ Faith Org. Support, 1998-2015 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Senior Fraud and Elder Abuse Prevention Training Workshop, Westminster Presbyterian Church, Albany, 1999 (Video-tape 1)
- CDSIF Senior Lifetime Achievement Ceremony Booklets, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Steering Committee, 2001-2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Forum Newsletters, 2002-2018 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Senior Lifetime Achievement Awards, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Senior Issues Honorees, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lifetime Achievement Awards Ceremony, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Meeting Mins/ Agendas/Committee Reports/Informational, 2009-2013 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Senior Lifetime Achievement Awards Ceremony Booklets, 2009-2014 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Fall Festival for Seniors, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Spring Festival for Seniors, 2010-2013 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Faith Communities Response to End of Life Issues, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Howard Hubbard Dedication, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Meeting Minutes/Agendas, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Senior Lifetime Achievement Awards Ceremony, 2015-2018 (Box 1, Folder 26)